{"data":[{"question":"Ted kept quiet about the plan ___ lose his life.","a":"so as not to","b":"so not as to","c":"not so as to","d":"so as to not","answer":"1","explain":"\n- So as (not) to + V= so that ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Owen reached the peak of the mountain and stopped ___ on a big rock by the side of the path.","a":"resting","b":"to have rested","c":"rest","d":"to rest","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Stop + V_ing: Don't continue doing something \n- Stop + To Verb: stop (doing) something to do something ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The secretary burnt the midnight oil, ___ a long speech for the president.","a":"preparing","b":"to prepare","c":"was preparing","d":"prepared","answer":"1","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and modifies a word farther up in the sentence, you will need a comma. The pattern looks like this: main clause + , + participle phrase. ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Can't you read? said Melissa ___ to the notice.","a":"and point angrily","b":"angrily pointing","c":"and angrily pointing","d":"angrily pointed","answer":"2","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase.","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The visiting Minister expressed his satisfaction with the talks, ___ that he has enjoyed his stay here.","a":"to add","b":"having added","c":"added","d":"adding","answer":"4","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and modifies a word farther up in the sentence, you will need a comma. The pattern looks like this: main clause + , + participle phrase","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Do you know the lady ___ on the big bed?","a":"lain","b":"lay","c":"lying","d":"laying","answer":"3","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase. ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"There was a loud noise ___ the sudden flash of light.","a":"following","b":"followed","c":"being followed","d":"to be followed","answer":"1","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase. ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"When Prof. Lin got back to his research room, he saw a note pinned to the door ___ \"Sorry to miss you; will call later.\"","a":"reads","b":"read","c":"that read","d":"to read","answer":"3","explain":"\n- That: introduces essential clauses","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The beautiful picture ___ on the wall was painted by my nephew and niece.","a":"hanging","b":"having hung","c":"being hung","d":"hangs","answer":"1","explain":"\n- When a participle phrase concludes a main clause and is describing the word right in front of it, you need no punctuation to connect the two sentence parts. The pattern looks like this: main clause + participle phrase.","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"___ a reply, the job applicant decided to write again.","a":"Receiving not","b":"Not receiving","c":"Having not received","d":"Not having received","answer":"4","explain":"- We use perfect participle (having past participle)","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"73","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"}]}